Guide to the Three Rivers Second Nature Project Records, 1948-2005 AIS.2006.19B
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- References, VII.
  - Bound Publications, 2.
    - "Endangered and Threatened Species of Pennsylvania" by: Pennsylvania Game Commission, Pennsylvania Fish and Boat Commission, and Bureau of Forestry, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "School of Forest Resources Biennial Report" by: Penn State University, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Native Plants in the Creation of Backyard, Schoolyard, and Park Habitat Areas" by: Audubon Council of Pittsburgh, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Biennial Assessment of Ohio River Water Quality Conditions" by: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "State Source Water Assessment and protection Programs Guidance: Draft Guidance" by: Environmental Protection Agency, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Partnerships for Environmental Health Education" by: National Association of County and City Health Officials, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Pollution Control Standards for Discharges to the Ohio River: 1997 Revision" by: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Restoration Ecology Journal, The Journal of the Society for Ecological Restoration Vol. 5 No. 4S", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Stream Corridor Restoration: Principles, Processes, and Practices" by: U. S. Department of Agriculture, U. S> Environmental Protection Agency, Tennessee Valley Authority, Federal Emergency Management Agency, U. S> Department of Commerce, U. S. Department of Defense, U. S. Department of Housing and Urban Development, and U. S. Department of the Interior, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
    - "Pennsylvania Stream Relief: A Plan for Restoring and Conserving Buffers along Pennsylvania Streams" by: Department of Environmental Protection, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "Inventory and Monitoring of Biotic Resources in Pennsylvania" Proceedings of the First Conference of Pennsylvania Biological Survey, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "What's Working on Working Rivers: A Handbook for Improving Urban Rivers" by: Naomi Cohn, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Report of the Pennsylvania 21st Century Environment Commission", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "Experiences with Urban Stream Quality Management" by: Nancy Schultz, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "1948-1998 A Fifty-Year Pursuit for Clean Streams" by: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Ecological Restoration 95-629", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Earthday Snapshot of Water Quality" by: The Pennsylvania Department of Environmental Protection, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Work Plan: A Study of Impacts and Control of Wet Weather Sources of Pollution on Large Rivers" by: The Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Terrestrial and Palustrine Plant Communities of Pennsylvania" by: Jean Fike, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Regional Long Term Wet Weather Control Concept Plan Draft" by: Allegheny County Sanitary Authority, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "Plumbing the Future: Seage Infrastructure and Sustainability in Western Pennsylvania" by: Environmental Law Institute, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "Daylighting: New Life for Buried Streams" by: Richard Pinkham, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Quality Monitor: An Appraisal of Conditions in the Ohio River and some of its Tributaries" by: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "Water Quality Phase I, Executive Summary" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "Alcosan Regional Long-Term Wet Weather Control Concept Plan: Municipal Comments and Alcosan Response" by: Allegheny County Sanitary Authority, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - "Program Plan" by: Ohio River Valley Sanitation Commission, 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - "Riverlife Task Force: A Progress Report" by: Riverlife Task Force, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - "Accepting the Challenge: A Primer about History, Cause, and Solutions to Abandoned Mine Drainage" by: Slippery Rock Watershed Coalition, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - "Stream restoration and Daylighting Phase I" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - "Social Project Reports Phase 2" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - "Terrestrial Project Reports: Monongahela River Valley Phase 2" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - "Monongahela and Youghiogheny Rivers pools 2 and 3 Riverbank Geology, Conditions, and Access Reports Phase 2" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - "The Citizen's Plan: An Alternative to the Pennsylvania Turnpike Commission's Plan to Complete the Mon-Fayette Toll Road" by: Citizens for Pennsylvania's Future, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "Ecological Restoration Vol. 20 No. 4), 2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "Three Rivers Second Nature Terrestrial Reports: Allegheny River Phase 3" by: the STUDIO for Creative Inquiry, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Living Rivers and Streams of Allegheny County Draft Proclamation" by: Three Rivers Second Nature Outreach Advisory Committee, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Mid-Atlantic Highlands Action Program: Transforming the Legacy" by: Canaan Valley Institute, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "Biodiversity in Pennsylvania" by: Pennsylvania Biodiversity Partnership, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "Water Monitoring for Watershed Planning and TMDLs" by: Wesley M. Jarrell, University of Illinois, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Back to Prosperity: A Competitive Agenda for Renewing Pennsylvania" by: The Brookings Institution Center on Urban and Metropolitan Policy, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Waterways and Wildlife: A Guide to Assessing and Improving Riparian Buffer Habitat" by: Nell Hanssen, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "Root Shock: Connecting People and Communities to Pittsburgh's Three Rivers" by: Find the Rivers! Partners, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "Find the Rivers! River Opportunity Report" by: Find the Rivers! Partners, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Regional Cooperation for Water Quality Improvement in Southwestern Pennsylvania" by: National Research Council of the National Academies, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Relationship Between Ohio River Water Quality and Drinking Water Quality" by: Ohio Valley River Sanitation Commission, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "We All Live Downstream: A Benefit for Conservation Consultants" by: Equitable Gas, Undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Audio-Visual Material, VIII.
  This series contains 39 folders and 25 items arranged thematically. There are four subseries labeled negatives, photographs, slides, and loose audio-visual material. The first three subseries contain folders and each folder's title is derived from the binder that the item came from or the title the item was given. The negatives, photographs, and slides are predominately undated, but what is dated ranges from 2000 to 2002. The fourth subseries, loose audio-visual material, contains 25 items of various mediums including a disc (CD-ROM), floppy disks, VHS tapes, videocassette tapes, and zip drives. The audio material is also predominately undated, but what is dated ranges from 1999 to 2003.
  - Negatives, 1.
    This subseries contains four folders of negatives that record the people involved and the geographic areas included in the Three Rivers Second Nature Project. The negatives range from 2000 to 2001.
    - July 6, 2000-May 6, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - May 6, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Undated (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Photographs, 2.
    This subseries contains 31 folders of photographs that record the people involved and geographic areas included in the Three Rivers Second Nature Project. The photographs were taken from eight binders, which correspond to the eight binder titles present in the folder titles. The rolls listed within each binder correspond to the roll of film to which those pictures belong.
    - Binder 1: "Roll no. 1 to 10" (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Binder 1: "Roll no. 11 to 19" (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Binder 1: "Roll no. 20 to 27" (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Binder 1: "Roll no. 28 to 38" (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Binder 1: "Roll no. 39 to 41" (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Binder 2: "Roll no. S-1 to S-10" (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Binder 2: "Roll no. S-11 to S-25" (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Binder 2: "Roll no. S-26 to S-35" (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Binder 2: "Roll no. S-36 to S-42" (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Binder 2: "Roll no. S-43 to S-47" (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Binder 3: "Roll no. T-2 to T-11" (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Binder 3: "Roll no. T-12 to T-17' (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Binder 3: "Roll no. T-18 to T-24" (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Binder 3: "Roll no. T-25 to T-29" (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Binder 3: "Roll no. T-30 to T-36" (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Binder 4: "Roll no. U-1 to U-6" (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Binder 4: "Roll no. U-7 to U-13" (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Binder 4: "Roll no. U-14 to U-21" (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Binder 5: "Roll no. U-18 to U-23" (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Binder 5: "Roll no. U-24 to U-25" (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Binder 5: "Roll no. U-26 to U-28" (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Water" Binder (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
    - "Education" Binder (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
    - "Water/Ben 2" Binder (Box 7, Folder 17-19)
    - Loose Photographs (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Slides, 3.
    This subseries contains four folders of slides that record the people involved and geographic areas included in the Three Rivers Second Nature Project. The slides were taken from tow binders; one untitled and one titled Cliff McGill, which is reflected in the folder titles. The slides range from 2000 to 2002.
    - 2000-2002 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "Cliff McGill" Binder (Box 8, Folder 2-4)
  - Computer Disk, 4.
    - "Monongahela River Movie" (Box 9, Item 1)
  - Floppy Disk, 5.
    - "Bridge Final Class", 2001 (Box 9, Item 2)
    - "Bridge Final Class", 2001 (Box 9, Item 3)
    - "Mon(ongahela) and Allegh(eny) Mile Markers" (Box 9, Item 4)
    - "Ohio River Mile Markers" (Box 9, Item 5)
    - "3R2N Stream Study" (Box 9, Item 6)
    - "3R2N Water Q", 2001 (Box 9, Item 7)
  - Camcorder Tapes, 6.
    - "Allegheny", 2000 (Box 9, Item 8)
    - "Monongahela", 2000 (Box 9, Item 9)
  - Zip Disks, 7.
    - "3R2N" (Box 9, Item 10)
    - "3R2N River Dialogues one and two" (Box 9, Item 11)
    - "3R2N Tim Collins" (Box 9, Item 12)
    - "3R2N Tim Collins and Reiko Goto" (Box 9, Item 13)
    - "Allegheny" (Box 9, Item 14)
    - "Botany Excel", 2003 (Box 9, Item 15)
    - "Fall Reiko", 1999 (Box 9, Item 16)
    - "Images M-2 and M-3" (Box 9, Item 17)
    - "Monongahela" (Box 9, Item 18)
    - "Ohio" (Box 9, Item 19)
    - "River Dialogues", 2001 (Box 9, Item 20)
    - "River Dialogues two" (Box 9, Item 21)
    - "Urban Watershed Images M-4" (Box 9, Item 22)
    - "Urban Watershed Text", 2001 (Box 9, Item 23)
  - VHS, 8.
    - "Down the Ohio left side" (Box 9, Item 24)
    - "Down the Ohio right side" (Box 9, Item 25)
- Maps, IX.
  This series contains maps that were created or used during the Three Rivers Second Nature Project. The legal-sized maps are housed in one box and roughly focus on the same topic, which is finalized, or working, copies of the areas of the rivers and streams that were examined. The data collected maps convey information that was obtained during the course of the waterway evaluation, such as present pollutant levels. Planning maps convey information about the planning process of the waterway evaluations, such as possible areas to build up.
  - Legal-sized map material (Box 10)
  - Data Collected (Map-case ??, Folder 1)
  - Planning (Map-case ??, Folder 2-3)